Myers, Malinda; Papers apap310
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Malinda Myers
1951-2003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap310
0.4 cubic ft.
This collection contains materials from Malinda Myers' work with the NAACP, Schenectady branch, and Schenectady County Community College.
Collection X
Access
The collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2009.
Historical Note
Malinda Myers was an active resident of Schenectady, New York, serving as the first female president of the Schenectady branch of the NAACP from 1959-1964, and in 1965 as chair of the 49-member Community College Feasibility Study Committee, which resulted in the establishment of Schenectady County Community College. She was also involved with the Schenectady public library and with the Church Women United, a women's movement to promote racial, cultural, and theological inclusivity. Myers died in July 2016 at the age of 96.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials from the NAACP, Schenectady branch, including minutes, (1951-1955 and 1961-1962); other NAACP records; materials about Schenectady County Community College; photographs; clippings; and records related to Malinda Myers' other community activities such as Myers' work with the public library. Not all dates are inclusive.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
African Americans -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Community organization--New York (State) --Schenectady; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Schenectady, New York; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. Schenectady Branch; Schenectady County Community College; African Americans and Civil Rights Organizations
- Activism Pamphlets and Correspondence, 1971-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Centennial Observance of the Signing of the Emancipation Proclamation, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Commencement Address to the Graduating Class of Schenectady County Community College, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1954; 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "Discrimination in Rental Housing: A Study of Resistance of Landlords to Non-White Tenants", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- NAACP 29th Annual State Convention Booklet, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- NAACP Brief Histories, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- NAACP Newspaper Clippings and Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People and Its Strategy Publications, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- New York Statewide Recreation Program Directions Booklet and Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Newspaper Articles, 1966; 1968; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Photographs of Malinda Myers and NAACP Members, and Newspaper Clipping, 1960-1961; 1964; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Schenectady Branch NAACP Bulletin, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Schenectady Branch NAACP Election Ballot and Proposed Budget, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Schenectady Branch NAACP Membership Meeting, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Schenectady Branch NAACP Tenth Anniversary Program and Fifteenth Anniversary Program, 1959; 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Schenectady County Community College Tenth and Thirtieth Anniversary Programs, Newspaper Clippings, and Photograph, 1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Schenectady County Public Library Black History Month and Other Literature, 1971-2003 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Schenectady NAACP Inaugural Awards Diner and NAACP Journal, 2003; Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Transcripts of the NAACP Schenectady Branch Meetings, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Transcripts of the NAACP Special and Regular Schenectady Branch Meetings, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 21)